(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
イケナイ太陽
作詞・作曲：ORANGE RANGE
Ikenai Taiyou
Lyrics & Composition: ORANGE RANGE
Fu-fu!
Ya ya ya ya
イケナイ太陽
Naughty Sun
Na na na na na na na nai
ちょっとでいいから 見せてくれないか
Just a little bit, won't you show me?
お前のセクシー・フェロモンで オレ メロメロ
With your sexy pheromones, I'm head over heels
溢れ出しそうでもイケナイの 序々に
Even if it seems like it's about to overflow, it's a no-no, gradually...
高鳴る鼓動 止められないわ
I can't stop this pounding heart
交わす言葉の 記憶遠く
The memory of the words we exchanged is far away
唇の動きに 揺れ動く
Swaying with the movement of your lips
濡れた髪を 撫でた そして
I stroked your wet hair, and then...
Ah! ABC 続かない
Ah! ABC won't continue
そんなんじゃダメじゃない
That's just no good, isn't it?
だってココロの奥は 違うんじゃない?
After all, isn't it different deep in your heart?
オレの精春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't just that
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to finish hot deep inside
きっとキミじゃなきゃヤダよ
It's gotta be you, or I don't want it
オレはイケナイ太陽
I'm the naughty sun
Na na na na na na na nai
赤い糸なんて エソラゴト
A red thread of fate is just a pipe dream
でも下心でさえ 信じたいの
But I want to believe even in ulterior motives
俺は正しい キミも正しい
I'm right, you're right
とにかくもう 左右されないで
Anyway, don't be swayed anymore
騙し騙され 胸うずく
Deceived and deceiving, my heart aches
下手な芝居がより 盛り上げるよ
Bad acting makes it even more exciting
息が耳に 触れた 二人
Our breaths touched our ears, the two of us...
Ah! ABC 続かない
Ah! ABC won't continue
そんなんじゃダメじゃない
That's just no good, isn't it?
だってココロの奥は 違うんじゃない?
After all, isn't it different deep in your heart?
あたしの精春 そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't just that
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to finish hot deep inside
きっとキミじゃなきゃヤダよ
It's gotta be you, or I don't want it
あたしイケナイ太陽
I'm the naughty sun
Fu-fu!
Ya ya ya ya
交わす言葉の 記憶遠く
The memory of the words we exchanged is far away
唇の動きに 揺れ動く
Swaying with the movement of your lips
濡れた髪を 撫でた そして
I stroked your wet hair, and then...
Ah! ABC ABC...
大掃除…続かないそんなんじゃダメじゃない
General cleaning... that's no good if it doesn't last
だって心の奥は違うんじゃない？
Because deep in your heart, isn't it different?
俺の青春そんなもんじゃない
My youth isn't just that much
熱く奥で果てたいよ
I want to finish hotly deep inside
きっと君じゃなきゃやだよ
I'm sure it's got to be you
俺はいけない太陽
I am the naughty sun
絡み合う糸は君と
The intertwined threads are with you
俺を結ぶ赤い糸
The red string of fate that binds me
Na na na na na na na...
はい！あ、あ、あ、あいということで！
Okay! So, so, so!
はい皆さん、こんまっする！ホロライブ3期生の…
白銀ノエルです！
Hello everyone, Kon-muscle! I'm Shirogane Noel
from Hololive Gen 3!
いきなりなんか、さざなみの音が…いきなりさっきまで
聞こえてない音が聞こえ始めたんですけど
Suddenly, I hear the sound of ripples...
Sounds I didn't hear until just now started playing.
イエーイ！いきなり生パートでやっております！
Yay! We're starting with a live segment!
いや、コメント見えてるよ。 「奥で果てるって
どういう意味？」みたいなこと書いてありましたけど
Yeah, I can see the comments. Someone wrote,
"What does 'finishing deep inside' mean?"
それは、あの、調べてくださいね、ウェブで。
Well, uh, please look that up on the web.
てかそういう話をしたいんじゃなくて…
Anyway, that's not what I wanted to talk about...
えっと、今回、白銀ノエル3周年迎えました！
Um, it's Shirogane Noel's 3rd anniversary!
えっと、こちら！こちらのハッシュタグ #白銀ノエル3周年記念 でね、いっぱい呟いてぜひぜひ盛り上げてくれると嬉しいです！
Um, here! Please use the hashtag #ShiroganeNoel3rdAnniversary and tweet a lot to hype things up!
そして水着です！
And I'm in a swimsuit!
今日はね、ちょっと水着とか色々着て
夏の思い出作りたいと思います！
Today, I'll wear swimsuits and stuff to
make some summer memories!
なんと！尺が1分しかないんで、
ちょっと急いで行きたいと思います！
Actually! I only have 1 minute for this part,
so I have to hurry!
あとスーパーチャットもコメントもありがとう！
Also, thanks for the Super Chats and comments!
あの、このあとメン限があるかもしれないんで、
あのギフトとかも配っちゃってもいいですよ！
Well, there might be a member-only stream later,
so feel free to give out gifts too!
ということで、えっと、準備して行きます！
So, um, I'll go get ready!
まだまだ続くんで、盛り上がってください！
It's still going, so please stay hyped!
ああ、いそいそいそ！頑張ってね！
Ah, hurry, hurry! Good luck!
あ、頑張ってねって自分が頑張るんだ！
Wait, I'm telling myself to work hard!
あやー！
Ayaa!
あの一等星のさんざめく光で
あなたとダンスを踊ろうか
Under the twinkling light of that first-magnitude star,
shall we dance together?
我が太陽系の天等に合わせて
絡まったステップで煌めいて、星！
To the rhythm of our solar system's celestial lamps,
sparkle with tangled steps, star!
Oh oh oh oh...
散漫になってる二人 空で
ラヴネブな猛座らって 連夜眠れない
Two drifting in the sky,
catching love-nebu wild constellations, sleepless night after night
星座になって混ざりどんな
一等星もあなたに変わる鼓動はないわ
Becoming a constellation and merging, no matter which
first-magnitude star it is, none match the heartbeat for you
そうじゃないんだ あの日 あなた見つけた奇跡さえ
今も離れない
That's not it, even the miracle of finding you that day
won't leave me now
隣にしげく見える目当てもあいにく今は興味がないわ
Unfortunately, I have no interest in any other targets
that often appear nearby
星が混ざっちゃって 胸が鳴っちゃって
気づけばあなた
Stars are mixing, my heart is pounding,
and before I knew it, it was you
あの一等星のさんざめく光で
あなたとダンスを踊ろうか
Under the twinkling light of that first-magnitude star,
shall we dance together?
我が太陽系の法則に誘われ
交わった感度で煌めいて、星！
Invited by the laws of our solar system,
sparkle with our intersected sensitivity, star!
Oh oh oh... 星間線を繋いで
Oh oh oh... Connecting the interstellar lines
Oh oh oh... あなたに届け
Oh oh oh... Reaching out to you
Oh oh oh... 宇宙の果てから
Oh oh oh... From the edge of the universe
Oh oh oh... あなたに進行形！
Oh oh oh... Progressing toward you!
Na na na na na na na...
大体のダンスは星が光る標となるさ
未体験のステップで、ハハハ
Most dances become a sign as the stars shine,
with unexperienced steps, ha ha ha
大胆な作戦 視界堂々 勝るのさ
太陽系のデスコで、ハハハ
A bold strategy, superior in plain sight,
at the Solar System Disco, ha ha ha
宙点火 いつか二人忘れることさえ今は求めたい
Ignition in space, I want to seek even the moment
we both forget one day
どうせと願う暮れた世界も不思議と今はとてもいいわ
The darkened world I wished away is
surprisingly good right now
何も無くたってなんとなくたって星は巡って
Even if there's nothing, even if it's just somehow, the stars go 'round
あの一等星の遠くの光は
遥かな彼方で煌めいた
The distant light of that first-magnitude star
sparkled in the far-off distance
我が太陽系の法則も外れて
それでもいいさ 手を伸ばして、さあ！
Even deviating from the laws of our solar system,
it's fine, reach out your hand, come on!
一星構想 やっとした思い出
あなたのすべて求めようか
One-star concept, memories finally made,
shall I seek everything about you?
何光年の広大な旅路で
比翼の連理を探そうか
On a vast journey of many light-years,
shall we look for the inseparable wings?
あの一等星のさんざめく光で
あなたとダンスを踊ろうか
Under the twinkling light of that first-magnitude star,
shall we dance together?
ほら水金だって地火木土天海も
二人の銀河で煌めいた、星！
Look, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, Neptune,
all sparkled in our galaxy, star!
Oh oh oh... 星間線を紡いで
Oh oh oh... Weaving the interstellar lines
あなたに届け
Let it reach you
宇宙の果てから
From the edge of the universe
あなた進行系！
You're in progress!
3周年おめでとうございます！
Congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
ちょいちょい、おめめパチパチ
Wait, wait, my eyes are blinking...
興奮しすぎてしまった
I got way too excited.
いや、ちょっと団長ね
Well, I mean...
こよりちゃんがまさか団長のライブに来てくれるなんて嬉しい
I'm so happy that Koyori-chan actually came to my live.
こよりの方こそまさかノエル先輩が呼んでくれるなんて
The same goes for me, I can't believe Noel-senpai invited me.
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much.
しかもですね、実はこより、この3Dで
And actually, for me, appearing as a guest
ゲストに出させていただくの今日が初めてなんです！
in 3D like this, today is my very first time!
おー！やったー！
Oh! Yay!
初めて奪われちゃいました
I've taken her first time.
ちょっと嬉しいけど、団長責任は取りません
I'm a bit happy, but I won't take responsibility.
ちょっと待ってください！こっちが先に責任...
Wait a second! I'll take responsibility first...
いや、こよりちゃんだったらそういうこと言うだろうなと思って
I just knew you'd say something like that.
えー、先に取ってくれないんですか？
Eh, you won't take it first?
じゃあ、何かしてほしいことあったりする？
Well then, is there anything you want me to do?
じゃあ、ずっとあの、後ろから抱きしめてもいいですか？
Then, can I hug you from behind?
いいんですか？初めてのそういう先輩とのMCというか...
Is it okay? For my first MC with a senior like this...
だからこそ、好きなこと言っちゃってもいいかなと思って
That's exactly why I thought I'd ask for what I want.
あー、じゃあちょっといいですよ
Ah, well, sure.
いいんですか？！
Really?!
はい、じゃあ、よいしょ
Yes, okay, here we go.
これなんかタイ...
This feels like the Ti...
タイタニック！
Titanic!
今、写真撮ってね
Take a photo now.
風を感じる！
I feel the wind!
ちょっと嬉しい。あ、見て、脇お互い見えるで
I'm so happy. Oh, look, our armpits are visible.
本当だ！
You're right!
これが脇ライブ
This is the Armpit Live.
そうだね、こよりちゃん、これからいっぱい脇ライブしていこうな
That's right, Koyori-chan, let's do lots of Armpit Lives together.
はい、していこう！
Yes, let's!
それでは、この後も楽しんでくださいね
Well then, please enjoy the rest of the show.
この後ね、団長もちょっとお着替えするからさ
I need to go change my outfit now.
一緒に帰るかい？
Shall we head back together?
しかも、これ言っちゃっていいんですか？
Also, is it okay to say that?
いいよいいよ
It's fine, it's fine.
もちろん団長についていけば大丈夫だから。ここ段差とかあるからね、気をつけて
You'll be safe as long as you follow me. There's a step here, so watch out.
わかりました。団長と同じ動きでいきますよ
Got it. I'll match your movements exactly.
行くよ、じゃあ！
Here we go then!
次は、行くぜ！
Next up, let's go!
うわああ！やべ、落ちる！
Waaaah! Oh no, I'm falling!
団員さん、まだまだ盛り上がっていくねー！
Knights, let's keep the excitement going!
ドキッ！こういうのが恋なの？
作詞・作曲 つんく
Doki! Kouiu no ga Koi nano?
Lyrics & Composition: Tsunku
ねえ　歌うわ
Hey, I'll sing
そうよ　あなたに
That's right, for you
甘えたいけど
I want to be spoiled
恥ずかしいかもね
But it might be embarrassing
願い事の呪文
The spell of a wish
ほら　ムニャムニャムニャ
Look, mumble mumble mumble
ずっとこのまま
Just like this forever
時が止まるかもね
Time might just stop
こういうのが恋なのかな
Is this what love is like?
ドキドキドキドキ
Pound, pound, pound, pound
かもね　かもね
Maybe, maybe
好き　好き　好き
Love, love, love
昨日よりも
More than yesterday
かもね　かもね
Maybe, maybe
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
ほめのび / 白銀ノエル
作詞・作曲・編曲：渡辺翔
Homenobi / Shirogane Noel
Lyrics, Comp, Arr: Watanabe Sho
どうにしようか
What should I do?
練習中
I'm practicing
しれっとこっそり準備進行
Secretly preparing, progress ongoing
心境 緊張
State of mind, nervous
ああ焦る
Ah, I'm panicking
言わんけどツヨツヨありでしょう
I won't say it, but I'm strong, right?
元気配るから上々って
I'll share my energy, so it's all good
そうやって成長する子です
That's how I grow
いいかな？
Is it okay?
ゆるぽちゃでおｋ
Slightly chubby is OK
1 2 3 テンパっちゃっておｋ
1 2 3 Panic is OK
始めちゃおう
Let's get started
ほめてほしいな
I want to be praised
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I'm the type that grows when showered with praise
もう！
Geez!
何も出てこない
Nothing comes to mind
頭ん中真っ白だ
My head is a complete blank
さっぱりだ うっうっあれ？
Totally empty, uh-uh what?
ま、いっか
Oh well, whatever
デコボコな情緒提供
Providing bumpy emotions
ポカンとしてるの？しーっ
Are you staring blankly? Shh
多分こんなんが通常のあたし
This is probably the usual me
いいでしょ？
It's fine, right?
それでそれでOK
That's that, OK
1 2 3 落ち着きOK
1 2 3 Composure is OK
始めちゃおう
Let's get started
どうしたらいいの？
What should I do?
どうすれば皆ハッピーで
How can I make everyone happy
笑顔がバッチリ
And full of smiles
こちらへどうぞ
Please come this way
焦らず慌てず並んで合図です
Don't rush, don't panic, line up for the signal
もう！
Geez!
聞こえてる
I can hear you
みゃみゃみゃ
Mya mya mya
楽しんでる？
Are you having fun?
ぽんぽんぽん
Pon pon pon
こっちだよ！
Over here!
少し眠いな
I'm a little sleepy
また明日 食べて寝て
See you tomorrow, eat and sleep
今は成長期
It's my growth period now
夢を見たいな
I want to dream
どうぞくれぐれもあの今後とも
Please, by all means, from now on too
ほめてほしいな
I want to be praised
ほめてくれたら2割増しで頑張る
If you praise me, I'll work 20% harder
見ててほしいな
I want you to watch me
ほめちぎられて伸びるタイプです
I'm the type that grows when showered with praise
またね！
See ya!
はーい！ということで、えっと...
Alright! So, um...
水着だよー！
It's a swimsuit!
イエーイ！びっくりしたびっくりしたびっくりした
Yay! I'm surprised, surprised, surprised!
ということで、えーと、水着になってからは...
So, um, after changing into the swimsuit...
「ドッキ！こういうのが恋なの？」と「ほめのび」を
I sang 'Dokki! Kouiu no ga Koi nano?' and
歌わせていただきました。歌ってダンスしましたー！
'Homenobi'. I sang and danced!
いや、ちょっとね、団長気付いた人いるかな？って
思ってちょっとチラチラ見てたんですけど。
Well, I was glancing around thinking if anyone noticed.
そう、太陽系デスコ、「ドッキ！こういうのが恋なの？」、ほめのび。
Right, 'Taiyoukei Disco', 'Dokki! Kouiu no ga Koi nano?', 'Homenobi'.
この3曲、1stフェスからね3rdフェスまでの
団長のソロで歌った曲になります！
These three songs are the ones Danchou sang solo
from the 1st to the 3rd anniversary!
やっぱりね3周年ということで、まあ成長してたかな？ダンス。
Since it's the 3rd anniversary, I wonder if my dancing has grown?
でもなんか、ちょっと2曲続けてはね、やっぱりちょっとね。
But singing two songs in a row is still a bit...
団長もっともっと体力つけたいなと思います！
I want to build up more and more stamina!
で、こっからはソロではなく、ゲストさんを呼んで
歌って踊ってやりますので...
From here on, it's not a solo; I'll be calling
guests to sing and dance, so...
まだまだ盛り上がっていってください！
Please keep the excitement going!
では、行ってきます！
Well then, here I go!
まだまだ見ててねー！
Keep watching!
絶対絶滅 Summer Knight
Zettai Zetsumetsu Summer Knight
満点決めて All Night
Get a perfect score all night
ヤバイ ヤバイ マジで
Crap, crap, seriously
ワニとシャンプー
Crocodile and Shampoo
作詞・作曲：前山田健一
Lyrics/Composition: Kenichi Maeyamada
灼熱 大太陽の時代で
In the scorching era of the great sun
こんがり小麦色
A toasted wheat-colored tan
ライブ ビキニ 肝試し
Lives, bikinis, courage tests
最高の夏休み
The best summer vacation!
ふと気づけば31日
Suddenly I realize it's the 31st
真っ青な空の色
The color of the deep blue sky
ずっとカバンで眠ってた
It's been sleeping in my bag all along
手つかず山積みプリント
A mountain of untouched printouts
X+Y=CIA
(オーストラリアの首都は) → ありません
(Australia's capital is) → None!
(法隆寺を建てたのは) → 卑弥呼様
(Who built Horyuji?) → Himiko-sama
意味不明
Makes no sense!
Where do you live now? Yes, I do.
(酸素を作るには?) → ワニとシャンプー
(To make oxygen?) → Crocodile and shampoo
ヤバイ! ヤバイ! ヤバイ! マジでヤバすぎる!
It's bad! It's bad! It's bad! This is seriously too bad!
終わらない 終わらない 全然全然終わらない
8月最終日の宿題
It won't end, it won't end, it won't end at all!
Homework on the last day of August.
適当にやってもしょうがない
でも適当にやるしかしょうがない
Doing it sloppily is no good,
but I have no choice but to do it sloppily!
とりあえずひたすら書きまくれ
For now, just keep on writing!
わからない わからない 全然全然わからない
もう少し手加減してよ 宿題
I don't get it, I don't get it, I don't get it at all!
Go a bit easier on me, homework!
誰かのせいにはしたくない
でも自分のせいにはしたくない
I don't want to blame anyone else,
but I don't want to blame myself either!
残り80枚 終わらない宿題
80 pages left! Never-ending homework.
大体済まさなーい 根絶ケツ終わらなーい
Most of it isn't done! It'll never end to the bitter end!
ヤバイ! ヤバイ! マジでヤバイ!
It's bad! It's bad! Seriously bad!
修業式から今日が来るまで
From the closing ceremony until today,
毎日駆け抜けた
I've been running through every day.
キャンプ イベント スイカ割り
Camping, events, watermelon splitting...
大切な思い出
Precious memories.
忘れてたわけじゃないけど
It's not that I'd forgotten, but...
大きな忘れ物
I've left behind something huge.
きっとなんとかなるでしょう
I'm sure it'll work out somehow!
シャーペン握って大決戦
Grabbing my mechanical pencil for the final battle!
(読書感想文) → 使い回し
(Book report) → Reused
(お天気) → 毎日くもり
(Weather) → Cloudy every day
ヤバイ! ヤバイ! ヤバイ! マジでヤバすぎる!
It's bad! It's bad! It's bad! This is seriously too bad!
終わらない 終わらない 全然全然終わらない
8月最終日の宿題
It won't end, it won't end, it won't end at all!
Homework on the last day of August.
後悔したってしょうがない
でも後悔するしかしょうがない
Regretting it is no good,
but I have no choice but to regret it!
神様時間を戻してよ
God, please turn back time!
わからない わからない 全然全然わからない
もう少し手加減してよ 宿題
I don't get it, I don't get it, I don't get it at all!
Go a bit easier on me, homework!
言い訳なんかはしたくない
でも言い訳するしか仕方ない
I don't want to make excuses,
but I have no choice but to make excuses!
残り70枚 終わらない宿題
70 pages left! Never-ending homework.
時間だけが過ぎていくけど
Only time keeps passing by...
出口はまだまだ先の先
The exit is still way, way ahead.
SOSメール出しても
Even if I send an SOS email...
返信0件
0 replies.
自業自得 因果応報
You reap what you sow, karmic retribution...
四面楚歌
Completely surrounded.
2学期なんか来なくてもいい!
The second semester doesn't even have to come!
あ、終わんない
Ah, it won't end!
終わらない 終わらない 全然全然終わらない
8月最終日の宿題
It won't end, it won't end, it won't end at all!
Homework on the last day of August.
適当にやってもしょうがない
でも適当にやるしかしょうがない
Doing it sloppily is no good,
but I have no choice but to do it sloppily!
とりあえずひたすら書きまくれ
For now, just keep on writing!
わからない わからない 全然全然わからない
もう少し手加減してよ 宿題
I don't get it, I don't get it, I don't get it at all!
Go a bit easier on me, homework!
誰かのせいにはしたくない
でも自分のせいにはしたくない
I don't want to blame anyone else,
but I don't want to blame myself either!
残り60枚 終わらない宿題
60 pages left! Never-ending homework.
はぁー、ヤバイ!
Phew, that was bad!
ノエルちゃーん!
Noel-chan!
3周年!
3rd Anniversary!
3周年、おめでとう!
Happy 3rd Anniversary!
ありがとうございます!
Thank you very much!
いや、ちょっとな、団長ね、夢があってさ。
Well, you see, I had a dream...
だって、3期生みんなさ、夏デビューじゃないっすか。
After all, all of us in the 3rd generation debuted in summer, right?
夏デビューに夏の曲を、しかも水着で!
So it was my dream to sing a summer song...
歌って踊るのが夢だった! やったー!
and in swimsuits, too! We did it! Yay!
最高だね。
It's the best.
だってさ、うちらね、水着なかったからさ。
Because, you know, we didn't have swimsuits back then.
確かに! 嬉しいね。
That's true! I'm so happy.
ちょうど3期生のころでしたからね、ホロライブサマーが。
Hololive Summer was just starting around the time of the 3rd generation.
そう! ちょ、フレアがさ、ぺこらっちょを仰ぐと...
Right! Hey, when Flare fans Pekora...
ウサギ鍋だよ。
It's rabbit hot pot.
違うぺこ! 食べないぺこ!
No it's not-peko! Don't eat me-peko!
ちょうど出汁が出来上がって...
The broth is just about ready...
鍋いらねーぺこで! いらない!
I don't need the pot-peko! I don't want it!
で、何? そうだね。
Anyway, what? Oh, right.
じゃあちょっとせっかくだから、この海をバックにさ、写真とか撮っちゃいませんか?
Since we're here, why don't we take some photos with the sea in the background?
撮りましょう!
Let's do it!
うわー
Uwaa!
どんな？
What's this?
でもやっぱさこれ扇あるからさ、なんかこんな感じで扇っぽくさ、やろうぜ
But since we have these fans, let's do something like a fan pose.
扇っぽくさ
Like a fan?
そう、こんな感じ、こんな感じでさ、体こうやってさ、こうやって、みんなで扇を作る
Yeah, like this. Move your body like this, and we'll all form a fan together.
え、どういうこと？
Eh, what do you mean?
あ、こういうことね
Ah, like this.
じゃあ船長、こっち、こうで、こうやって
Then Captain, here, like this, and do this...
あ、いいね、そうそうそう
Ah, nice, that's it.
イェーイ！
Yay!
ね、これが撮りたかったの
See, this is the shot I wanted.
どんな絵面？
What kind of shot is this?
撮りたかった？
You wanted to take this?
え、違くないか？
Wait, isn't something off?
なんかの...
Like some kind of...
こうみんなでさ、こうやってさ、仮面舞踏...マスカレード
Everyone together, like this... a masquerade... Masquerade!
あ、いいじゃん
Oh, that's cool.
え、それなんかちょっとマリンがやるとあれだな
Wait, if Marine does that, it's a bit...
え、何、ど、ど、ど、どういうことですか？
What? What do you mean by that?
顔隠す...な、こうやってね、こうね
Hiding your face... like this, right?
チラ、チラ、チラ、あ、いいですね。隙間から、隙間から
Peek, peek, peek... ah, that's nice. Through the gap, through the gap.
イェーイ
Yay
え、本当にこれでいいのか？
Wait, is this really okay?
うーん
Hmm...
あ、なんかイチャついちゃった。なんでー、みんなで写真撮るんじゃーん
Oh, they're flirting. Why?! We were supposed to take a picture together!
ね、元気出して、マリンはノエル王だから
Hey, cheer up. Marine is the Noel King, after all.
マリンはノエル王だよ
Marine is the Noel King.
そうだよ。そうだよ
That's right. That's right.
あの、今絶賛さ、夏は3期生のさ、4週連続企画で、明日はペコラっちの枠があるからな。イェーイ！
Um, right now it's summer, and the 3rd gen has a 4-week consecutive project. Tomorrow is Pekora-chi's turn! Yay!
誰がペコらかわかんなくなるね
No one will know who Pekora is.
はいはい、絶対行く、絶対行く、絶対、絶対
Yes, yes, I'll definitely go, definitely go, definitely, definitely.
私、私、私、私、私！
Me, me, me, me, me!
楽しいペコだね、今日ね
It's a fun day, peko.
さあ、だからね、ちょっとま、みんなちょっとここでね、今日はバイバイしちゃうけど、明日も会えるからね
So, you know, everyone will say goodbye here for today, but we'll see each other again tomorrow.
そうだ、そうだ
That's right, that's right.
やだー、もうやだー
No way, I don't want to!
じゃあ2人置いていくか
Shall we leave those two behind?
置いていこう、行こう、バイバイ、バイバイ
Let's leave them. Let's go. Bye-bye, bye-bye.
えー、早い、おねー、やだー
Wait, so fast! Older sister, no way!
じゃあ明日もよろしくね、あ、ライブまだ続くよー
Then, looking forward to tomorrow too. Oh, the live performance is still continuing!
そこそこあそこ見つからないぜ パパイヤマンゴーココナッツ
Here, there, anywhere, can't find it / Papaya, mango, coconut
かき氷 いちご味 ベロを出したら 真っ赤っか
Shaved ice, strawberry flavor / Stick out your tongue, it's bright red
ココ☆ナツ
Coco☆Natsu
イモーション 水着ショット ジャジャジャジャジャジャジャーン
Emotion, swimsuit shot / Ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-jaan!
ココ☆ナツ イェーイ！
Coco☆Natsu, yay!
カチカチに燃えてるお日様
The sun is burning intensely
バッシュワ ココナッツ ベイビー
Ba-shwa, coconut baby
待ちわびた季節はサマーサマー
The long-awaited season is summer, summer
バッシュワ ココナッツ ベイビー
Ba-shwa, coconut baby
甘い期待しちゃったビキニ すごく照れるけど
The bikini I had sweet expectations for / I'm so embarrassed but...
すごく照れるけど 負けらんない
I'm so embarrassed but I won't lose
日焼け止め ココナッツ フレーバー
Sunscreen, coconut flavor
バッシュワ ココナッツ ベイビー
Ba-shwa, coconut baby
紫外線とこなつレーザー
UV rays and everlasting summer laser
バッシュワ ココナッツ ベイビー
Ba-shwa, coconut baby
サンキュッキュッ 君の視線 心臓
Thank-q-q, your gaze / My heart...
心臓 大爆発
My heart is a massive explosion
サシスセソココナッツベイビー
Sa-shi-su-se-so, coconut baby
タチツテトココナッツベイビー
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to, coconut baby
カキクケココナッツベイビー
Ka-ki-ku-ke-ko, coconut baby
ササササマータイム！イェス！
Su-su-su-summertime! Yes!
コココココココココ...
Co-co-co-co-co-co-co-co-co...
かき氷 メロン味 ベロを出したら ゾンビだーい
Shaved ice, melon flavor / Stick out your tongue, you're a zombie!
勝負浴衣で ボンダンス ジャジャジャジャジャジャジャーン
In a competitive yukata, Bon dance / Ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-ja-jaan!
それ！ジョイナジョイナジョイナジョイナ
There! Join-a, join-a, join-a, join-a!
むしむしアンベアデッタイヤー
Humid and unbearable, it's summer!
バッシュワ ココナッツ ベイビー
Ba-shwa, coconut baby
ココナッツジュースみたいな
Like coconut juice
長いようで短いサマータイム
A summertime that seems long but is short
バッシュワ ココナッツ ベイビー
Ba-shwa, coconut baby
やっちゃったもん勝ち
First come, first served!
サシスセソココナッツベイビー
Sa-shi-su-se-so, coconut baby
タチツテトココナッツベイビー
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to, coconut baby
カキクケココナッツベイビー
Ka-ki-ku-ke-ko, coconut baby
ササササマータイム！イェス！
Su-su-su-summertime! Yes!
コココココココココ...
Co-co-co-co-co-co-co-co-co...
ココ☆ナツ
Coco☆Natsu
セイヤ！
Seiya!
アチアチのサマー 手作り羽 追い風極上ジャンップ最大級
Hot, hot summer, handmade wings / Maximum jump with a top-class tailwind
さささのココナツベイビー
Sasasa's coconut baby
たちつてとのココナツベイビー
Tachitsuteto's coconut baby
なにぬねののココナツベイビー
Naninuneno's coconut baby
かきくけこのココナツベイビー
Kakikukeko's coconut baby
さささのココナツベイビー
Sasasa's coconut baby
たちつてとのココナツベイビー
Tachitsuteto's coconut baby
なにぬねののココナツベイビー
Naninuneno's coconut baby
かきくけこのココナツベイビー
Kakikukeko's coconut baby
燦々サマータイム
Brilliant summer time
Yes!
コココココココココココーナツ
Co-co-co-co-co-co-co-co-co-coconuts
ココ☆ナッツ
Coco Nuts
どこどこあそこ見つからないぜ
Where, where? I can't find it anywhere
パパイヤマンゴーココナッツ
Papaya, mango, coconuts
ナッツ！
Nuts!
（歓声）
(Cheers)
みなさーん、こっちー！
Everyone, over here!
カメラこっちだよー、カメラ！
Camera's over here! Camera!
ちょ、触らないでくださいよー
Hey, don't touch me!
イエーイ！夏だー！
Yay! It's summer!
ノエル先輩 3周年おめでとうございます！
Noel-senpai, congratulations on your 3rd anniversary!
かわいい！かわいい！
So cute! So cute!
罪の可愛さよ
Such sinful cuteness.
我々水着ですよ
We're in swimsuits!
そうですよ、水着！
That's right, swimsuits!
みんなで水着とかやばっ！やばー！
Everyone in swimsuits is crazy! So crazy!
いやなんかね、団長あれですよ。やっぱりね、ももクロの曲をこのメンバーで歌ったのも理由わかるよね？
Well, Danchou... you know. There's a reason we sang a Momoclo song with this group, right?
もちろん、もちろん！
Of course, of course!
わかるよーあれ、みんなわかるよねー？
I know! Everyone knows, right?
わかるよねー！
We know!
じゃあ、せーのでいきましょう。
Then, let's say it on 'Ready, set...'
私たち...
We are...
もものんサマータイム！
Momonon Summertime!
いやでもしかもね、今回さ、歌って踊ってみて気づいたんだけど、この4人いいわ。
But really, singing and dancing this time made me realize... these four are great.
めっちゃ助かる。それぞれの系統がいて、めちゃめちゃバランスがいいなと思いました。
So true. Each of us has a different style, so the balance is perfect.
属性がもう分かれてる！
Our attributes are already distinct!
4人でさ、ちょっと写真撮りません？
Why don't the four of us take a photo?
せっかく水着ですからね。
Since we're in swimsuits and all.
どんな感じで？
How should we do it?
振り返って...
Turn around...
振り返り美人！
Back shot beauties!
ポ、ポルカのしっぽがやばくてさ。
P-Polka's tail is in the way.
ちょっと待って。
Wait a second.
ちょっと待って、後ろ向くからちゃんと。
Wait, I'll turn around properly.
触らないでー！
Don't touch me!
これがいいんだよ、これが！
This is what makes it good!
ル、ルイ姉しっぽないの？これしっぽ？
L-Lui-nee, you don't have a tail? Is this a tail?
私シャチだからないのよ。
I'm an orca, so I don't have one.
あ、かわいい！
Oh, cute!
あ、かわいいねー。
Oh, how cute.
ハッシュタグで呟いてね！
Tweet with the hashtag!
いやみんな熱い。
Man, everyone's hot.
蒸気めっちゃ出てる！
There's so much steam!
バレちゃった。
Caught me.
いやなんかさ、あれだ、でも時間がね、限られててさ。もうそろそろ...
Well... but time is limited. It's almost time to...
えー！ここにいたい！
No! I want to stay here!
本当嫌だー！動かない！
I really don't want to! I'm not moving!
ちょっと遊ぼうよ。足ふやけちゃうからね。
Let's play more. But your feet will get wrinkly.
え、じゃあでもさ、やっぱ団長もね、このあとね、あれなんですよ。海からね、ちょっと変わりましてなんで。
Well... but Danchou also has to... after this. We're changing from the sea setting.
お着替えするんで、みんなとお着替えしたいから...
I'm going to change clothes, so I want to change with everyone...
行っちゃうか！
Shall we go?!
あとでシャワー浴びる？
Want to take a shower later?
シャワー浴びる？
Take a shower?
いいな。じゃあ一緒にシャワーだ！
Sounds good. Let's take a shower together!
じゃあ行きますよ、一緒にシャワー。
Okay, here we go, shower time together.
行きます、せーの！
Here we go, ready, set...!
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten already?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the summer shade?
アイスを口に放り込んで
Tossing an ice pop into your mouth,
風を待っていた
Waiting for the breeze.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten already?
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
The world is full of nothing but lies.
本当の価値を二人で
How we laughed about
探しに行こうと笑ったこと
Going to find the true value together.
忘れないように
So I won't forget,
色褪せないように
So it won't fade,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
So that physical things aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words.
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming.
僕が描いてる
What I'm painting,
目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
What was reflected in my eyes, is a ghost of summer.
風にスカートが揺れて
Your skirt sways in the wind,
思い出なんて忘れて
Forget all about the memories,
浅い呼吸をする
Taking a shallow breath.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, becoming summery.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Maybe you've already forgotten
夏の木陰に座った頃
The time we sat in the summer shade
遠くの丘から顔出した
The clouds that peeked out
雲があったじゃないか
From the distant hills
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to catch them
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
With your hands swinging wildly at the air
僕は紙に雲のひとつを書いて
I drew a cloud on a piece of paper
笑って見せて見せて
And showed it to you with a smile
忘れないように
So I don't forget
色褪せないように
So it doesn't fade
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because history isn't everything
今だけ顔も無くして
Just for now, lose your face
言葉も全部忘れて
Forget all your words
君は笑ってる
You're laughing
夏を待っている 僕らそれだけ
We're waiting for summer, that's all
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me about the scent of summer
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths
忘れないように
So I don't forget
色褪せないように
So it doesn't fade
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because not everything that resonates is everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words
さよならだって教えて
Tell me about goodbyes too
今を見るんだよ
Look at the present
夏に咲いている花に亡霊を
Ghosts in the flowers blooming in summer
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but heart
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping away sweat, it feels like summer
夏の匂いがする
It smells like summer
もう忘れてしまったかな
Maybe you've already forgotten
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Still sitting in the summer shade
アイスを口に放り込んで
Tossing ice cream into our mouths
風を待っていた
Waiting for the wind
あなたは今どこで何をしていますか？
Where are you now and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか？
Are you in a place where this sky continues?
今まで私の心を埋めていたもの
The things that have filled my heart until now
失って初めて気付いた
I realized for the first time after losing them
こんなにも私を支えてくれていたこと
How much you were supporting me
こんなにも笑顔をくれていたこと
How many smiles you were giving me
失ってしまった代償は
The price of losing you is
とてつもなく大きすぎて
Far too immense
取り戻そうと必死に
Desperately trying to get you back
手を伸ばしてもがくけれど
Reaching out my hand and struggling, but...
まるで風のようにすり抜けて
Slipping through like the wind
届きそうで届かない
Almost reaching, but not quite
孤独と絶望に胸を締め付けられ
My chest is tightened by loneliness and despair
心が壊れそうになるけれど
My heart feels like it's about to break, but...
思い出に残るあなたの笑顔が
Your smile that remains in my memories
私をいつも励ましてくれる
Always encourages me
もう一度 あの頃に戻ろう
Let's go back to those days once again
今度は きっと大丈夫
This time, it'll surely be okay
いつもそばで笑っていよう
Let's always stay together with a smile
あなたのすぐそばで
Right there by your side
あなたは今 どこで何をしていますか
Where are you now and what are you doing?
この空の続く場所にいますか
Are you somewhere that this sky continues to reach?
いつものように笑顔でいてくれますか
Are you smiling, just like you always used to?
今はただそれを願い続ける
Now, I just keep on wishing for that
はい！ということで
Yes! So with that said...
どうでしょうか、団長の浴衣になります！
How do you like it? This is Danchou's yukata!
ちょっとね、大人っぽい感じ？
It's a bit of a more adult look?
それとも子供っぽい感じ？ どんな感じでしょうか？
Or maybe a bit childish? What do you think?
いつもわちゃわちゃしてる動きのせい、子供っぽくなっちゃうんですけど
I guess my usual restless movements make me look a bit childish, though.
えっと、「花に亡霊」と「YOU」を聴いていただきました
Um, you just listened to "Hana ni Bourei" and "YOU".
本当、夏にぴったりの曲だなと思っていて
I really think these songs are perfect for summer.
団長この曲すごく大好きなので、こうやって浴衣で歌えて良かったです
I love these songs so much, so I'm glad I could sing them in a yukata like this.
座りで歌って踊るってあんまりないから、新鮮だったんじゃないかなって思います
Singing and dancing while sitting down is something I don't do often, so it might have been a fresh experience.
このあとね、またお着替えをして
After this, I'm going to change my outfit again.
別のところで、歌って踊りますので
And then I'll be singing and dancing in a different place.
最後までよろしくお願いいたします！
So please stay with me until the very end!
では！また着替えてくるんでね、待っててね！着替えてきまーす！
Alright then! I'll go change now, so wait for me! I'm going to change!
ぱっぱら働く 休むことなく ロドロドラッタッタ
Working, working, without a break. Rodo rodo ratta tta.
繰り返しの毎日 気が付けば迷子の猫のよう
Day after day repeating, before I know it, I'm like a lost cat.
どっかで誰かが入れ替わろうと マノマノランランラン
No matter who's replaced somewhere, mano mano ran ran ran.
誰も気付かない ひたすらに数字を追い掛けた
No one notices, just single-mindedly chasing numbers.
心の奥底には 鍵をかけた扉
In the depths of my heart, a door that's been locked.
馬鹿げてる そう言い聞かせては
It's ridiculous, I tell myself that.
ノックの音を無視した
And ignored the sound of knocking.
変わらないと諦めて 佇む時計の
Resigned to things not changing, standing still by the clock's...
針に急かされる
Hand, being hurried along.
夢ならば喜んで 星に願い事を
If it were a dream, I'd gladly make a wish upon a star...
真面目な顔で
With a serious expression.
チクタク働け 焦げた兵士 ガタンガタンラッタッタ
Work tick-tock, scorched soldier. Gatan gatan ratta tta.
昼夜選択用意ドン 気が付けば真っ黒屑のよう
Day and night, choice, ready, go. Before I know it, I'm like pitch-black soot.
朝と夜とが入れ替わろうと ノマノマランランラン
No matter how day and night switch, noma noma ran ran ran.
誰も気にしない 貪欲に数字を追い掛けた
No one cares, greedily chasing numbers.
扉の向こう側から 幽かに漏れる声
From the other side of the door, a voice faintly leaking through.
仕方ないと 膝立てて
Saying it can't be helped, I pull my knees up
部屋の隅っこで
in the corner of my room,
小さく罵声を吐く
I quietly spit out insults.
何処でもいい 連れ出して
Anywhere is fine, take me away.
王子様なんて来るはずもなく
There's no way a prince will ever come.
こんばんは おはようございます
Good evening, good morning.
扉の向こうで誰かが言う
Someone says from the other side of the door.
大丈夫 鍵は開けたわ
It's okay, I've unlocked it.
ここからあなたに届くでしょう
It should reach you from here.
そんな話は聞きたくない
I don't want to hear that story.
聞きたくない
I don't want to hear it.
いや 聞きたくない
No, I don't want to hear it.
ねえねえ どこにも行かないで
Hey, don't go anywhere.
そばにいて
Stay by my side.
話を聞かせて
Tell me your story.
下らないと 嘘吐いて
Saying it's worthless, I tell a lie.
それでも誰かに気付いて欲しくて
Still, I want someone to notice me.
気付いて欲しくて
I want them to notice.
冷たくて 震えたくない
It's cold, and I don't want to shake.
いつまで経っても鍵は開けられずに
No matter how much time passes, the door remains locked.
棺の中 働いて
Working inside a coffin.
それでもまあなんて言いたくはないわ
I don't want to say things like "even so".
針は回る いつまでも
The clock hands spin, forever and ever.
優しいノックの音で泣いてしまう
I end up crying at the sound of a gentle knock.
だんご だんご だんご だんご
Dango, dango, dango, dango
だんご 大家族
Dango, a big family
だんご だんご だんご だんご
Dango, dango, dango, dango
だんご 大家族
Dango, a big family
やんちゃな 焼きだんご
Mischievous grilled dango
やさしい あん だんご
Kind bean-paste dango
少し 夢見がちな
A slightly dreamy
月見だんご
Moon-viewing dango
おすまし ごまだんご
Proper sesame dango
よつご 串だんご
Quadruplet skewered dango
みんな みんな あわせて
Everyone, everyone, together
100人 家族
A family of a hundred
あかちゃん だんごは
Baby dango are
いつも しあわせの中で
always in happiness
としより だんごは
Elderly dango
目を細めてる
are squinting their eyes (smiling)
なかよし だんご
Close-knit dango
手をつなぎ
hold hands
大きなまるい輪になるよ
and form a big, round circle
町をつくり だんご星の上
They build a town on the Dango Star
みんなで 笑いあうよ
and they all laugh together
うさぎも空で 手を振ってみてる
The rabbit in the sky is waving too
でっかいお月様
at the giant moon
うれしいこと かなしいことも
Happy things, and sad things too
全部 まるめて
They roll them all together
だんご　だんご　だんご　だんご
Dango, dango, dango, dango
だんご　だんご　大家族
Dango, dango, big family
仲良しだんご　手をつなぎ　大きな丸い輪になるよ
Friendly dangos holding hands to make a big round circle
町をつくろう　だんご星の上
Let's build a town on the dango planet
みんなで笑いあおうよ
Let's all laugh together
うさぎも空で　手をふってみてる
Even the rabbits in the sky are waving their hands
でっかいお月様
At the giant moon
嬉しいこと　悲しいことも
Happy things, sad things too
全部まるめて
Rolling them all together
ラララ…
La la la...
だんご　だんご　だんご　だんご　だんご　だんご　大家族
Dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, dango, big family
はい、ということで、みんな見えとる？
Alright, so, can everyone see me?
ちょっと目が開かねえ…うっ…
My eyes won't open... ugh...
あれ？みんなのコメントが見えない。ちょっと待ってね。
Huh? I can't see everyone's comments. Wait a second.
あ、開いた開いた！あ、みんな…
Ah, they opened! Ah, everyone...
めちゃめちゃ拍手してくれてる！ありがとう！
You're giving me so much applause! Thank you!
今日はね、あの、いつもと違って収録と生パートのね、こう二つでやっております。
Today, unlike usual, we're doing a mix of pre-recorded and live parts.
こちら、はい、コメント見えておりますので。や、ありがとう！
I can see the comments here. Yeah, thank you!
あの、みんなコメントでね、なんかすごい夏を感じたりエモさを感じたりね、
Everyone's comments are full of summer vibes and feelings,
いろんな感情が爆発してる感じで、団長嬉しいなと思います。
It feels like various emotions are exploding, and I'm so happy.
ちなみにこのセトリは4ヶ月前だから、
By the way, this setlist was made 4 months ago,
お、4月、3月ぐらいに考えたセトリになっておりました。
So it was a setlist I thought of around March or April.
では、ちょっとね、ここからちょっと三つお知らせがあるんですけど、
Now, I have three announcements to make from here,
それ聞いてくれますか？
Will you listen to them?
ちなみにここも尺があるので駆け足になりますが、では、
I'm on a tight schedule here too, so I'll go through them quickly.
お知らせ一つ目！ドドンガドン！
First announcement! Drumroll, please!
活動3周年記念
3rd Anniversary Commemoration
はい！みんな待ってたかな？活動3周年記念！
Yes! Have you all been waiting? 3rd Anniversary of my activities!
ということで、グッズを出したいと思います。
So, I'd like to release some merchandise.
8月8日があの3周年だったんですけど、
August 8th was the 3rd anniversary,
このライブに合わせてちょっと遅らせてグッズを販売する感じになりました。
But we decided to delay the sales to match this live concert.
じゃ、ちょっとあれかな？詳しい商品とかを、紹介していきたいと思うんですけど、
So, I'd like to introduce the products in detail...
そう、直筆ね！サインとかあります。
Yes, handwritten! There are autographs.
あ、見えてる！あ、ちょっと…
Oh, I can see them! Oh, wait...
あ、ちょっとこれ見せちゃおうかな？見せちゃおうか！ズン！
Oh, maybe I should show you this? Let's show it! Boom!
ということで、ちょっとね、あ、なんか小さい団員さんがおるんですけど、
So, we have a little Dane-san here,
ちょっとその団員さん気になると思うんすわ。
I bet you're curious about this member.
こちら活動3周年記念フルセットの中身になりました。
This is the content of the 3rd Anniversary Full Set.
えっと、まあ、今ね、ちょっと制服で紹介させていただくんですけど、
Well, I'm introducing them in my school uniform now,
つい最近ね、新衣装をお披露目しました。
But I recently revealed my new outfit.
その新衣装に合わせた、なんと、団長とおそろいパーカーがあります！
And to match that new outfit, there's a hoodie just like mine!
え？マジ？え？
Wait, really? What?
待ってた待ってた！
I've been waiting for this!
ということで、皆さんちょっとぜひ、あの、団長とおそろっちになってください。
So, everyone, please get matching hoodies with me.
あの、このサムネもね、あの、団長のパーカー匂わせておりますので、
The thumbnail also hints at my hoodie,
ぜひぜひぜひ買ってください。
So please, please, please buy it.
で、えっと、団員専用シェイカー、マッスルシェイカーもあります。
Also, there's a Dane-san exclusive shaker, the Muscle Shaker.
これもね、まあ、夏の思い出ということで、わたを父上が描いたアクリルパネル、
This one too, and as a summer memory, an acrylic panel drawn by Watao-papa,
そうです、ポストカード、あの、あるんですけど、
And postcards too, we have them all.
まあ夏といえばね、汗かくんで。
Well, it's summer, so we sweat.
汗かいたら、ちゃんとタンパク質を補給しましょうみたいな感じで。
When you sweat, you should replenish your protein.
こちら気になってたでしょう？見て！
You were curious about this, weren't you? Look!
団員さんぬいぐるみキーホルダー！
Dane-san plush keychain!
こちらね、あの今回、あの、その団員さん、ライブでも左右にいたと思うんですけど、
This time, these members were standing on both sides during the live,
ああ可愛い！
Ah, so cute!
このぐらいのサイズ感。まあ、もうちょっと、もしかして小さいかな？
It's about this size. Or maybe a bit smaller?
って感じなんですけど、こんぐらいになっておりますので。
That's how it feels, but it's about this big.
これね、ぜひぜひ、あのカバンにつけて、
Please attach this to your bag,
「俺、団員だ」というアピールをしてください。
And show off that you're a member!
めちゃ可愛い！見て、見てる。
It's so cute! Look, it's watching.
お尻嗅ぎたいんですけど...
I want to sniff its butt, but...
あーありがとうございます！ちょっとお尻嗅ごうとしたら引きになっちゃった。
Ah, thank you! I tried to sniff the butt and the camera pulled back.
こちらね、あのぜひぜひめちゃめちゃ可愛いので。
This one, it's really, really cute, so please...
はい、ぜひお買い求めください！
Yes, please do buy it!
ということで時間が結構バタバタなんですけど。
Anyway, things are getting a bit hectic for time.
よいしょ、ちょっとダニさんどこに置こう？あ、持っとくか？
Heave-ho, where should I put Dany-san? Oh, should I just hold him?
かわいそうだから持っとこうかな。じゃあ持ちながらちょっと紹介したいと思います。
I feel bad for him, so I'll just hold him. I'll introduce the rest while holding him.
あと2つあるんですけど、えっともう一つが...
There are two more. The first is...
この後22時15分から、団長初めての「生面源」3Dをしたいと思います。
Starting at 22:15 today, I'll be doing my first 'Namamengen' 3D live.
いやー、ちょっと3D生ってどんな感じになるのか、ちょっとドキドキなんですけど。
I'm a bit nervous about how a 3D live stream will turn out.
たくさんね、あのメンバーギフトとかも配ってくれてありがとう！あとメンバーさんになってくれた方もありがとう！
Thank you so much for all the membership gifts! And thank you to those who became members!
いっぱいね、ちょっと衣装もありますので、その撮影会をしたいと思います。
I have many outfits, so I'll be doing a photoshoot session.
えっと、その撮影会は、あのスクショはOKです。
For that photoshoot, taking screenshots is okay.
TwitterでたくさんスクショをやるのはOKなんですけど...
Posting lots of screenshots on Twitter is fine, but...
切り抜きとか、映像はダメになっておりますので、ぜひぜひいっぱいスクショしてください。
Clipping or video recordings are not allowed, so please just take lots of screenshots.
ということで、あ、やべ！めちゃめちゃ時間押してるんですけど。
With that, oh no! I'm really running behind schedule.
最後！最後のお知らせです。
Last! Here is the final announcement.
この後ちょっと一曲歌わせていただくんですけど、最後に団長オリ曲歌います！
I'm going to sing one song after this, and it's my new original song!
オリ曲はこちらです！はい、ドドンガドンドン。
Here's the song! *Drumroll*
作詞作曲・古川本舗さんの「ours」という曲を歌わせていただきます。
I'll be singing 'ours', written and composed by Furukawa Honpo.
この後ね、22時5分からミュージックビデオも、はい、配信されるんですけど。
The music video will also be released starting at 22:05.
この「ours」、いや、すごいいい曲になってて。
This song 'ours', it's turned out to be so good.
まぁ古川本舗さんっていうね、あの有名な、はい、方がいるんですけど。
Furukawa Honpo is a very famous artist...
なぜその方にお願いしたかというと、団長「眠る魚」という曲が好きで。
The reason I asked him is because I love his song 'Nemuru Sakana'.
その「眠る魚」好きだから、その、なんかそういう「眠る魚」のようなゆったりとした...
Because I love it, I wanted a song with that kind of relaxed and...
そしてエモい曲が、うん、作りたいということでお願いいたしました。
...emotional vibe, so that's what I requested.
こちらね、歌詞に注目していただくとすごいんですけど。
The lyrics are also amazing if you pay attention to them.
「ours」はね、まぁ団員さんと団長の3年間の振り返りと...
'ours' is a reflection of the three years I've spent with my fans...
4年目もね、ずっと一緒に繋がろうといった思いが込められた曲になっておりますので。
...and it's filled with the desire to stay connected into our fourth year.
あの、もうめちゃめちゃ気持ちを込めて歌うので、よろしくお願いします。
I'll be singing with all my heart, so please enjoy.
本日24時からデジタルリリースもします。これからお披露目するのでよろしくお願いします。
The digital release is today at midnight. I'm performing it now, so here it is.
ということで、1分オーバーしました！これが「生」。ということで、あの、はけたいと思います。
So, I'm one minute over time! That's the nature of live streaming. I'll take my leave now.
じゃあ一緒に見ようね。あ、団長歌うんだった。じゃあ、よろしくねー！
Let's watch together... oh wait, I'm the one singing. Okay, here goes!
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
Today doesn't end with a goodbye
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand
秘密を眠りにつくような夜に
In a night that lulls secrets to sleep
君を連れていくよ
I will take you away
それは例えば、遠く離れていたって
Even if we are far apart
手を繋いでいられるような
It's as if we can still hold hands
奇跡のような話をしよう!
Let's talk about miracle-like things!
窓は開けておいて。
Keep the window open.
今日までを思い出して一つ、一つ並べたら
Recalling the days up until today, lining them up one by one
明日の雨が気になりだしてどうも眠れないみたいだ。
I start worrying about tomorrow's rain and can't seem to sleep.
変わりたくないことや変わらなきゃいけないことも
Things I don't want to change and things that must change
少し忘れたまま窓の外眺めていたんだ。
Forgetting them for a bit, I was gazing out the window.
あぁ雨が降り出すその前に
Ah, before the rain starts to fall
君のところまで行けるような気がして
I feel like I can make it to where you are
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes
そして、このまま遠くへと行こう!
And so, let's go far away like this!
手をとってくれるかな。
Will you take my hand?
秘密を眠りにつくような夜を
Through the night that lulls secrets to sleep
君と泳いでいくよ。
I will swim along with you.
街の明かりが消える度に笑って
Laughing every time the city lights go out
路地裏で抱き合おう。
Let's embrace in the back alleys.
馬鹿みたいな話をしよう!
Let's talk about silly things!
窓は開けておいて
Keep the window open
聞こえる?
Can you hear it?
聞こえる
I can hear it
今日みたいな 夜を重ねて 織り上げてきた
Woven together from nights like today,
私たちに響く音
the sound that echoes to us.
夜が来るたびに 心が躍ってしまうのは
The reason my heart leaps whenever night comes
また一つ重なっていくから
is because we're layering another memory.
目を閉じてみたんだ
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜 私たちだけで眠ろう。 誰にも言わないで。
Let's sleep just the two of us tonight. Don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつくその少し前に 名前を呼んで
Call my name just a little before you fall asleep.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで 俯いてしまうけど
My chest aches from unfulfillable wishes and I look down, but...
誰もいない街へ誘いに行くから
...I'll come to invite you to a town where no one else is.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ。 手をとってくれたなら
Today isn't goodbye just like this. If you take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に 君を連れていくよ。
I'll take you away on a night when even secrets go to sleep.
それは例えば、遠く離れていたって 手を繋いでいられるような
Like, for example, being able to hold hands even if we're far apart,
奇跡のような話をしよう！
let's tell a story like a miracle!
窓は開けといて。
Leave the window open.
聞こえる？
Can you hear me?
愛おしいことや 無くせないものを 教えてくれたのは
The one who taught me about precious things and things I can't lose
今日みたいな 夜を重ねて 織り上げてきた
was woven together from nights like today,
私たちに響く音、
the sound that echoes to us,
響く言葉。
the words that echo.
3周年ありがとう！！ すてきな夏の思い出になったかな！？
Thank you for the 3rd anniversary!! Did it become a wonderful summer memory!?
来年も再来年もずっと たのしい思い出つくろ！ 大好きだゾ～☆
Let's keep making fun memories next year, and the year after, and forever! I love you guys! ☆
4年目も 共に 歩もうね♡ Noel
Let's walk together in our 4th year too. ♡ Noel